aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
By receiving the fusion light wave from Dag Base,
다그 베이스의 합체 광파를 받아
En managed to combine to form Super Fire Dagwon,
슈퍼 파이어 다그온으로의 합체를 달성한 엔은
and took down the strongest alien, Zelma.
최강의 우주인 제르마를 훌륭하게 쓰러뜨렸다
But that quick energy drain also took away En's consciousness.
하지만 그 급격한 에너지 소모는 엔 자신의 의식도 잃게 하는 것이었다
Damn!
젠장…!
At this rate, the name of the Warugaia Brothers doesn't stand!
이대로라면 우리 와르가이아 형제의 이름이 서질 않아!
What is Hido being slow about?!
히도는 뭘 그리 꾸물대는 거야?!
I can't endure it anymore!
이젠 못 참겠어!
Brother, let's take down Dagwons by ourselves...
형, 우리 손으로 다그온 놈들을…
I see.
그렇군…
We might kill all the Dagwon by ourselves and
우리가 직접 다그온을 한명도 남김없이 말살해서
it might be a good idea to show those Space Police Organization brats what we're capable of.
우주 경찰 기구 놈들에게 본때를 보여주는 것도 나쁘지 않겠군
Brother!
형…
Our target is Dag Base!
표적은 다그 베이스다
Damn Dagwon...
다그온 녀석…
Damn Dagwon!
다그온 녀석…!
You'll see!
어디 두고봐라---!
The Cracked Dag Tector
부서진 다그 텍터
The Three Warugaia Brothers
Appear
와르가이아 3형제
등장
Kai, how's En doing?
카이, 엔의 상태는 어때?
He's pretty much exhausted, but his life is not in danger.
상당히 체력을 소모했지만 생명에 지장은 없어
I sent Rai to check out how he's doing now.
지금 라이에게 상태를 확인하러 보낸 참이야
That's good to hear.
그래, 일단 안심이네
Damn, those Three Warugaia Brothers!
젠장, 와르가이아 3형제 녀석들!
If they're willing to fight against us, then they should show themselves fair and square!
우리과 싸울 마음이 있다면 정정당당히 튀어나오란 말이야!
That's easy to say, but they aren't going to be taken down easily.
말은 쉬워도 간단히 쓰러뜨릴 수 있는 상대가 아니야
They are the strongest, worst brothers in Space.
녀석들은 우주 최악 최강의 형제야
There were numerous victims from the Space Police Organization too.
우주 경찰 기구에도 지금까지 수많은 희생자가 나왔어
If we didn't have Super Fire Dagwon, we don't know what would have happened with that strong alien.
어제의 우주인과의 싸움도 슈퍼 파이어 다그온이 없었다면 어떻게 되었을지 몰라
This is all the data about Super Fire Dagwon.
이게 슈퍼 파이어 다그온의 모든 데이터입니다
His might is definitely something...
확실히 그 위력은 상상을 초월합니다만
But to En, Super Blazing Fusion is definitely risk-staking.
엔에게 있어 초화염합체는
It definitely means that with it comes much danger.
확실히 위험이 동반한다는 거군
That's worrysome...
걱정되는걸…
It's alright.
괜찮아요
Ms. Maria is nursing En all day and night.
엔이라면 마리아 씨가 밤새 간병해 주고 있어요
He'll get well soon.
꼭 건강해질 거예요
I didn't think you really cared about En.
엔을 그토록 걱정하다니, 너…
We're looking at you, Geki!
다시 봤어, 게키
Idiot! I'm worried about Ms. Maria!
바보녀석! 내가 걱정하는 건 마리아 씨 쪽이라구!
Think about it!
생각해 봐라
A young boy and girl are having a night with only those two!
한창 때의 젊은 남녀 단 둘이서 하룻밤을 보내는 거라구
Think about them doing these things!
이런 거랄지 저런 걸 한다고 생각해 봐라!
They wouldn't.
안 해요…
Damn En! I will never forgive you!
엔 녀석!
절대 용서 못한다!
I should've expected that of that guy.
뭐 저런 놈이 다 있냐
En, just die!
엔 따윈 죽어버려!
Why did I say such a cruel thing?
왜 그런 심한 말을 해 버린 걸까
En!
엔…!
엔!
Are you awake now, En?
정신이 들었어, 엔?
M- Maria.
마, 마리아…
You'd better lie down some more.
좀 더 누워있는 편이 좋아
Why am I in the club room?
나, 어째서 부실에…?
I was here all the time, and suddenly those other guys brought you here.
내가 있을 때 갑자기 애들이 엔을 옮겨와서
You were asleep all the time since then; you wouldn't move a bit even when there was thunder.
그때부터 계속 잠든 채로 밤중에 벼락이 쳐도 꿈쩍도 안하더라
I worried that you were going to be in this state from now on...
계속 이대로 있으면 어쩌나 해서 걱정했어
Maria...
마리아…
Did you nurse me all night?
너, 밤새 날 간병해 준 거야?
But I couldn't just leave you there.
그치만, 그냥 내버려 둘 수 없어서…
But, En, what happened to you?
그런데 엔, 어째서 이렇게 된 거야?
Do you have any secrets?
네게는 무슨 비밀이라도…?
Maria...
마리아…
-Gaku! Rai!
-Yo!
-가쿠, 라이!
-여~
-Good morning.
-Morning.
-안녕
That's my immortal senpai!
역시 불사신 선배
It seems that you're alright now.
이제 괜찮은 것 같군요
Right, right!
그래 그래
But it sure is strange...
아무리 생각해도 이상한데
En is sick in bed?
엔이 몸져 눕다니 말이야
You cannot deceive my eyes. Is it a faked illness?
내 눈은 속일 수 없어 그럼 꾀병인가?
Or did you play too much at night?
아니면 밤놀이를 너무 많이 했나?
Tell me frankly!
솔직히 불어라~
Gaku!
가쿠!
What was that for?
무슨 짓이야?!
What's up with that truly scary face?
뭐야, 진짜로 무서운 표정 짓고…
It's not something fake.
꾀병 같은 게 아니야
En is really...
정말로 엔은…
Maria, I'm alright now.
마리아, 이제 괜찮다니까…
You see?
그치?
Look.
거봐
You must sleep for now, En!
아직 더 누워 있어야돼, 엔
Alright! I'll make some healthy food just for you, senpai!
좋았어! 제가 선배를 위해서 기운 나는 스테미너식을 만들게요
Unlike how I look, I'm pretty good at cooking!
이래뵈도 요리 꽤 잘 한다구요
Let's go, Rai.
가자, 라이
I was going to make food for senpai!
전 선배에게 식사를…
En...
엔…
I bought food for him!
모처럼 재료를 사왔는데…
You can leave the rest to Maria!
뒤는 누나한테 맡기면 돼
But-
그치만…
You're senseless, for being older than me!
나이도 많은 사람이 눈치 참 없네
We're just flies in the ointment!
우리는 방해꾼(お邪魔蟲)이라구
Flies?
방해꾼(お邪魔蟲)?
What bug is that?
그게 어떤 벌레(蟲)예요?
Never mind, Rai! Just speed up, or we're going to be late!
그것보다, 라이 좀 더 밟아봐, 지각하겠어~
If we speed up more than this, it's violating the law!
이 이상은 속도 위반이예요
It's fine! It's fine!
됐으니까 밟아~
You brats may die with Dagwon!
다그온과 함께 네놈들도 뒈져라!
What's wrong, Maria?
왜그래, 마리아?
Something must've happened at school.
학교 쪽에 무슨 일이 생긴 모양이야
-I hear screams.
-What?
-비명이 들려
-뭐야?
E- everyone!
여, 여러분!
There's nothing to worry about if you do as how we learned in the safety training!
재해 피난 훈련대로 하면 걱정 없어요!
Everyone calm down! Please calm down!
침착하세요!
침착하라니까~!
You should calm down first, vice principal.
자네야말로 침착하게, 교감 선생
Principal A- Asahiyama...
아, 아사히야마 교장…
What's going on?!
대체 이건…?!
I don't know.
나도 잘 모르겠네
Anyway, leading the students to a safe place is more important.
어쨌든 학생들을 안전한 곳으로 유도하는 것이 선결이네
Y- yes, sir!
예, 예!
That is Dag Base.
저게 다그 베이스다
Damn Dagwon, you're going to pay!
다그온 녀석들
이제 곧 놀랄 거다
En! You must sleep more!
엔! 아직 더 누워 있어야돼!
Maria...
마리아…
You are the one who shouldn't come to this place!
너야말로 이런 곳에 오지 말라구
I have something I must do.
내겐 꼭 해야만 하는 일이 있어
But!
그치만…!
You showed up, En.
납시셨구나, 엔
Y-you punk!
이자식…!
En! Help me!
엔! 살려줘!
Keep quiet!
입 닥치고 있어!
-Stop it!
-Don't move!
-그만둬!
-움직이지마!
Maria!
마리아---!
What's wrong, Yoku? Is it malfunctioning?
무슨 일이야, 요쿠? 모든 기능이 조작 불능 보초라도 발생한 거야?
That is... all the functionalities are out of our control.
그게…
The external communication has been dropped too!
외부와의 통신도 일체 차단당했습니다
What did you say?! What's the reason?!
뭐라고? 원인은?!
It seems that all of Dag Base is covered by some kind of strong force.
어떤 강력한 힘으로 다그 베이스 전체가 둘러싸인 것 같습니다
In other words, we are trapped inside Dag Base, and cannot get out of here!
다시말해, 우리는 다그 베이스 밖으로 한 발자국도 움직일 수 없게
No way!
갇혀버린 것과 마찬가지입니다
Is there even a force that can seal this powerful Dag Base?!
말도 안돼! 이 강력한 다그 베이스를 봉인시킬 수 있는 힘이 존재한단 말이야?!
Dagwon!
다그온!
The phrase "rat in a trap" was invented to describe you.
'독안에 든 쥐'라는 것은 딱 너희들을 일컫는 말이구나
Let us watch your final moments!
네놈들의 최후를 천천히 구경해 주마
Those bastards did it!
녀석들 짓이구나!
Mado and Gedo, of the Warugaia Brothers!
와르가이아 형제 마도와 게도!
Yoku, this is...!
요쿠, 이건?!
Abnormalities in the main power source!
주 동력원에도 이상 발생!
It started to congest and went out of control!
제어 불능으로 인해 폭주를 시작했습니다!
If it reaches the critical limit, Dag Base will shatter!
이대로 임계치을 넘어서면 다그베이스 째로 산산조각이…!
What?!
뭐라고?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
We're doomed! It's totally out of control!
틀렸어요!
완전히 조작 불능!
Come here, Thunder Shuttle!
Come here, 선더 셔틀
Thunder Fusion!
뇌명합체
(雷鳴合體)
Thunder Dagwon!
선더 다그온
Finally you came to invade Earth!
마침내 지구에까지 쳐들어왔구나!
Warugaia Brothers!
와르가이아 형제!
Damn... where did he run off to?
젠장, 어디로 도망쳤냐…
Who ran away?
누가 도망쳤다는 거지?
Hido.
히도…!
Now, in a place where nobody would interfere with us, let's finish this slowly, En.
자, 아무런 방해도 없는 곳에서 천천히 결판을 짓자구 엔…
I'll finish this whenever you want!
결판이라면 언제든지 지어 주마
But let Maria go first!
하지만… 그전에 마리아를 놔줘라!
Oh, of course, I'll let her go.
아~ 놔주고 말고
I have no interest in such a girl.
이런 계집에겐 볼일 없으니 말이지
Maria!
마리아!
I'll face you, as you wanted!
바라는대로 상대해 주마!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Fire En!
파이어 엔
What's wrong, Dagwon?
왜 그러나, 다그온?
If you die too soon, you aren't worth killing at all.
너무 빨리 뒈져버리면 죽이는 보람이 없다구
Dagwon...!
다그온…?
What?!
아니?!
Warugaia Brothers!
와르가이아 형제!
Give up your futile resistance and just sit, relax and watch your comrades explode with the base!
부질없는 몸부림은 그만두고 동료들이 기지 째로 날아가는 장면이라도 보고 있거라
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐야…?
3 minutes until the main power source explodes!
주 동력원 폭발까지 앞으로 3분!
What?!
뭐라고?!
Dagwon!
다그온!
Playtime ends now.
장난은 여기까지다
I'll kill you!
죽여주마!
Die!
뒈져라!
You're not running away!
안 놓친다!
You're not doing as you want!
맘대론 안된다!
Maria!
마리아!
En?
엔…?
You found out.
들켜 버렸네…
En! En! Hang in there!
엔…! 엔!
정신차려!
Hey! Open your eyes!
이봐! 눈 좀 떠봐!
En!
엔---!
I... I must do something...
어, 어떻게든 하지 않으면…
Too late!
이미 늦었다!
What?!
뭐라고?!
You'll pay!
이자식---!
Damn! Must we wait until we blow up doing nothing?!
젠장! 아무것도 못하고 이대로 날아가는 걸 기다리는 수 밖에 없냐?!
1 minute until the explosion!
폭발까지 앞으로 1분!
Ryu?!
류?!
40 seconds!
앞으로 40초!
30 seconds!
남은 시간 30초!
Damn!
제기랄!
20 seconds left! We're doomed!
앞으로 20초!
이제 틀렸어요!
You idiot! Don't say weak!
바보녀석!
냐약한 소리 하지마!
We are the Brave Dagwon!
우리는 용자 다그온이야!
We will absolutely never give up until the last moment!
절대 마지막까지 포기 안해!
That's right!
그 말대로다!
Warugaia Brothers, we will not let you scum do whatever you want!
와르가이아 형제 너희들 뜻대로 되도록 내버려 두진 않는다!
The main power source is now operating normally!
주 동력원이 정상치로 돌아왔습니다
All functions are restored!
모든 기능도 회복!
We did it!
-앗싸~
-성공이다~!
Brother!
형!
Damn that Brave Seijin!
브레이브 성인 녀석!
En.. En! Stay with me, En!
엔… 엔!
정신차려, 엔!
I win! I won against a Dagwon!
이겼다!
다그온을 이겼다구!
Go to hell together as friends!
둘이 사이좋게 저세상으로 가라!
Die!
뒈져라!
Brave Seijin?!
브레이브 성인?!
Hido!
히도!
A victory for you brats will never be obtained!
네놈들의 승리 따윈 영원히 없다!
Shut up! I'll kill you first!
닥쳐!
네놈부터 죽여주마!
B- brother!
혀, 형!
Curse you, Brave Seijin! How dare you do that to Hido! Unforgivable!
이놈!
브레이브 성인! 잘도 히도를!
용서 못한다!
En!
엔!
Unforgivable, Dagwon!
용서 못한다, 다그온!
I'll make you pay by all means!
반드시 네놈들에게 복수해 주마!
As soon as we're done with burying Hido, we'll come back again!
히도의 매장이 끝나면 우리는 또다시 돌아올 것이다!
That time will be the last moment of you bastards!
그때가 바로 너희들의 최후다!
P- principal... our school...
교, 교장 선생님…
학교가…
It doesn't matter, as school buildings can be constructed again.
뭐, 학교는 다시 세울 수 있네
More importantly, it's good to know our students are safe and sound.
그것보다, 학생들이 무사해서 다행이네
Brave Seijin...
브레이브 성인…
Dear Dagwon.
다그온이여
I still take pride in choosing you guys.
나는… 너희들을 선택한 것을… 지금도 자랑스럽게 여기고 있다…
You guys will protect this beautiful Earth, and...
너희들이라면… 반드시 이 아름다운 지구를, 그리고…
...protect the justice of Space from the evil hands.
우주의 정의를…
Brave Seijin...
마수로부터 지켜내 주겠지…
I am looking forward to your great activities with all my heart.
브레이브 성인…
Farewell, dear Dagwon.
너희들의 활약을 진심으로 빌고 있다
It can't be...
안녕이다, 다그온이여…
Brave Seijin has died...
그럴수가… 브레이브 성인이… 죽다니…
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Brave Seijin has died. We have nobody to depend on anymore!
브레이브 성인이 죽어 버렸어 우리는 이제 누구에게도 의지할 수 없어!
Now our only option is to raid Sargasso by ourselves and destroy them!
이렇게 되면 이쪽에서 사르갓소에 쳐들어가서 직접 쳐부술 수밖에 없겠군!
Rai can control Dag Base. We're heading to Space tomorrow!
라이라면 다그 베이스를 조종할 수 있어 내일 우주를 향해 발진이다!
Then I'll declare my love to Erika before we depart!
그럼 출발 전에 나는 에리카에게 사랑의 고백을 해야지!
En, what'll you do?
엔, 너는 어쩔래?
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! To Space, our Brave Heroes
다음회 용자지령 다그온
용자들 우주로
We can't look back anymore!
이젠 한걸음도 물러서지 않아!
To Space, our Brave Heroes
용자들 우주로